Oh Pooh.
Winnie the Pooh is a animation, family, comedy film
directed by Stephen J. Anderson.
During an ordinary day in Hundred Acre Wood, Winnie
the Pooh sets out to find some honey.
Misinterpreting a note from Christopher Robin, Owl convinces Pooh, Tigger, Rabbit, Piglet, Kanga, Roo, and Eeyore
that their young friend has been captured by a creature named "Backson" and they set out to rescue him.
Winnie the Pooh / Tigger (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Eeyore (voice), played by Bud Luckey.
Owl (voice), played by Craig Ferguson.
Piglet (voice), played by Travis Oates.
Rabbit (voice), played by Tom Kenny.
Kanga (voice), played by Kristen Anderson-Lopez.
Winnie the Pooh is a 2011 American animated musical comedy
film produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
It is based on the book series by A.
Milne and is a revival of Disney's Winnie the Pooh franchise.
It was directed by Stephen Anderson and Don Hall.
Jim Cummings reprises his voice roles as Winnie the Pooh and Tigger,
and Travis Oates reprises his voice role as Piglet.
The voice cast also includes Tom Kenny, Craig Ferguson,
Bud Luckey, and Kristen Anderson-Lopez.
In the film, which is narrated by John Cleese, the residents of the Hundred Acre Wood embark on a quest to
save Christopher Robin from an imaginary culprit, while Pooh deals with a hunger for honey.
Production began in September 2008 with Disney Animation's chief creative officer John Lasseter
announcing that Disney wanted to create a film that would "transcend generations".
The film was planned to feature five stories from the A.
Milne books, before the final cut ended up drawing
inspiration from three stories.
The film features six songs by Kristen Anderson-Lopez and Robert Lopez and a score composed by Henry Jackman, as well as a
rendition of the Sherman Brothers' "Winnie the Pooh" theme song by actress and musician Zooey Deschanel.
Winnie the Pooh premiered at the Roy E.
Disney Animation Building in Burbank, California on July 10, 2011,
and was released in the United States on July 15.
The film grossed $50.1 million on a $30 million budget and received generally positive reviews
from critics, who praised the animation style but criticized its short runtime.
As of 2025, it is Disney Animation's most recent
traditionally animated theatrical feature film.
The film explores themes of tiger, donkey, cartoon, piglet, rabbit.
The tone is lighthearted.